<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cultivation-arts on Makotori</title>
    <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cultivation-arts on Makotori</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/measurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/measurement/</guid>
      <description>Measurement Devices for Monitoring Body Signals BITalino  BITalino (r)evolution Plugged Kit BT (170€) Casing Bundle for BITalino (r)evolution Plugged Kit BT (25€) Sensors  Electromyography (EMG) Sensor (22.50€)  to measure muscle activity   Electrocardiography (ECG) (22.50€)  to measure the electrical activity of the heart.   Electrodermal Activity (EDA) (25.00€)  to measure the changes in skin conductance resulting from the sympathetic nervous system activity.   Electroencephalography (EEG) (37.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tai Chi (太極)</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/tai-chi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/tai-chi/</guid>
      <description>Questions How do we define Taiji? Origin Story  Initially the universe was without life. All was foggy and blurry, without differentiation or separation, with no extremities or ends. This state was called 无极 (wújí, no extremes) Later the existing energy divided into two extremities, 阴 (yīn) and 阳 (yáng). This polarity, or tendency to divide is called 太极 (tàijí), the Grand Ultimate or Grand extremity. This initial separation allows and causes all subsequent divisions and changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wing Chun (詠春拳)</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/wing-chun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/wing-chun/</guid>
      <description>Glossary of Wing Chun terms
Wooden Dummy Section 1 (1-10)  Refighting Position  Neutral stance, left hand in front   Neck-pulling Hand  Pivot to left bring right shoulder forward Left hand passes upwards through dummy arms to grab dummy&amp;rsquo;s right forearm Right hand gets hold of &amp;ldquo;neck&amp;rdquo; of dummy Then both hand exert sudden force to throw dummy off balance   Right Bong-Sau  Stance stays pivoted left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga (योग)</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/yoga/</guid>
      <description>Ashtanga Yoga Primary Series  Complete Chart Video with David Swenson  David Swenson is one of only a handful of Westerners to have learned the full Ashtanga system including all of the asana sequences and pranayama as originally taught by K. Pattabhi Jois, who developed and popularized the vinyāsa style of yoga known as Ashtanga Yoga    Surya Namaskar (सूर्यनमस्कार) A ![](yoga-surya_namaskar_a.jpg &#34;yoga-surya_namaskar_a.jpg&#34;) yoga-surya_namaskar_a.jpg  Surya Namaskar (सूर्यनमस्कार) B !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditation (冥想)</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/meditation/</guid>
      <description>Goals of Meditation Absence of Self  One goal is really the remove the self, the ego, the entity in the mind that identifies with things and judges things. The result would be just the energy that is in the body, that is ever-connected with all things. So how does one reach this state while trying to reach this state, which is the self that&amp;rsquo;s trying to reach the state?  Do you force a habit of non-judgment via continual meditation practice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qigong (氣功)</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/qigong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/qigong/</guid>
      <description>Qigong has been shown to have benefits related to many bodily functions. Heart-brain-breathing interactions research has shown evidence for the benefits of meditation and qigong type activities. Key ideas
 Meditation and qigong breathing increases heart variability Resonant breath biofeedback  Greatest results with diaphragmatic breathing (WHY?) Baroreflex Individual&amp;rsquo;s resonant heart rate Measurement devices Sources  1      Research Qigong  A Comprehensive Review of Health Benefits of Qigong and Tai Chi Lin, Shin: Research Leading to a Systems/Cellular/Molecular Model for the Benefits of Qigong and Tai Chi on Health and Healing  Heart-Brain Interactions  McCraty, Rollin: The Coherent Heart Heart–Brain Interactions, Psychophysiological Coherence, and the Emergence of System-Wide Order Presentations  Videos  Qigong &amp;amp; Tai Chi - Evidence Based Medicine  Key concepts:  Qigong increased brain waves related to deep sleep and concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal</title>
      <link>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://petevieira.github.io/cultivation-arts/journal/</guid>
      <description>Explanation  Unless specified otherwise, meditation is done indoors and everything else is done outdoors. Stretching varies between indoor and outdoor. The purpose of this journal is to track my efforts and progress, as well as give me a way to go back and know what I did, how long, how consistently, etc, as well as to help me reflect more on my efforts.   2019-04-06 Mediation  Position: half-lotus Duration: 10 min Experience:  Very difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>